So here's a way to define Fibonacci iteratively.
这里有一种方法来迭代地定义 fibonacci
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[声音空白]
We're going to avoid all the redundant computation by keeping track as we
我们要通过跟踪运行轨迹 来避免所有的冗余计算
go. And we're going to have two variables. And I'm going to do this
我们将有两个变量 我要以一种稍微
in a slightly strange way, and the reason for this will become
有点奇怪的方式来做 而我这样做的原因很快就
clear soon. I want to make it so we can get the right
清楚了 我想获得正确的答案
answer when n is 0 and when n is 1, without having
当 n 为 0 和 1 的时候 先不考虑
special cases. So instead of keeping track of the previous two, I'm
特殊情况 所以不是跟踪前两个
going to keep track of the current one and the imaginary one that's
我要跟踪当前的值 和一个想象的
going to be after that. And we know that the first two Fibonacci
在它之后的值 我们知道前两个 fibonacci
numbers are 0 and 1, so the current is
数字是 0 和 1 所以现在 current 是 0
0, and the next one, we'll call after is 1.
然后下一个 我们称之为 after 是 1
So that's the one after the one that we're currently
所以这个是我们当前值的下一个
doing, and now we have a loop, so we're going to
现在我们有一个循环 我们将
go from i in the range from 0 to n.
使 i 在 0 到 n 的范围内
So we're looking for Fibonacci number n, that means we
所以我们正在寻找 fibonacci(n) 这意味着我们
want to start at 0. The current value is the value
要从 0 开始 current 的值是
for Fibonacci 0 and after is the value for Fibonacci
fibonacci(0) 的值 after 是 fibonacci(1) 的值
1, and as we go through the loop, we'll keep
当我们通过循环 我们将不断
updating those. And we want to update them by following the
更新它们 我们想要通过遵循递归规则来
recursive rule and so that means that the new value
更新它们 这意味着 current 的新值
of current, is the current value of after. And the new
是 after 的当前值
value of after, is the sum of those two, is
after 的新值 是它们的和 即
current plus after. We can do that with a multiple
current + after 我们可以用一个多重
assignment, that'll save us from needing a temporary variable. We
赋值 这将使我们省去一个临时变量 我们
can assign current and after, to their new values. The new
可以将新值分别赋值给 current 和 after
value of current, is the current value of after, and the
current 的新值 是 after 的当前值
new value of after is current plus after. So, this is
after 的新值 是 correct + after 所以 这就是
the place where a multiple assignment comes in handy. If we
多重赋值的灵活运用 如果我们
didn't use a multiple assignment, we'd have to use a temporary
没有使用多重赋值 我们必须在赋值时
value to keep track of one of these while we do
使用一个临时变量来跟踪其中的一个值
the assignments. But with multiple assignment, we get both of these
但是有了多重赋值 我们首先同时获取它们
values first, and then we assign them to the two variables
两个的值 然后将它们赋值给左侧的
on the left side. So, that's all we need. And then
两个变量 所以 这就是我们需要的全部 接下来
after the loop, we should return the value of
在循环后 我们应该返回 current 的值
current, which is the current Fibonacci number if we're looking
如果我们正在寻找 fibonacci(n) 这就是
for Fibonacci N. So let's try that. So we
那个数 所以让我们试试看 所以我们
should be able to see Fibonacci 0, and the result
应该能够看到 fibonacci(0) 结果
should be 0. And that's what we get, and
应该是0 这正是我们得到的
because that's the value of current, when the range is
因为这是 current 的值 当范围从
from 0 to 0, we don't go through the loop
0 到 0 时 我们根本不通过循环
at all. So we get the value 1. Let's check
所以我们得到值 1 (此处应是口误) 让我们检查
Fibonacci 1. And we run this, we get the value 1, which is also
fibonacci(1) 我们运行它 得到值 1 这也是
what we expect. And we got that because we went through the loop once, assigning
我们的期望值 我们获得这个值是因为我们经过了 1 次循环
the value of after, which started as 1 to current and that's what we
将从 1 开始的 after 的值 赋值给 current 也就是
return as the value of current. And we can keep going, we'll try Fibonacci 2.
我们返回的 current 的值 我们可以继续 我们将尝试 fibonacci(2)
And that's also 1, as we expect and Fibonacci 3
结果也是 1 正如我们期望的 然后 fibonacci(3)
should be 1 plus 1, gets us 2 and so forth.
应该是 1+1 我们得到 2 等等
[BLANK_AUDIO].
[声音空白]
Okay, so this looks like it's working. We've tried
好了 看起来它工作了 我们已经试过
a few simple ones. Let's try Fibonacci 33. So
几个简单的例子 让我们试试 fibonacci(33)
we estimated in the earlier quiz, in order to
我们在之前的练习中估计过 为了
compute fibonacci 36, we would need Fibonacci 33 calls,
计算 fibonacci(36) 使用之前的递归定义
using the previous recursive definition. So, why did it
我们将需要 fibonacci(33) 次调用 所以为什么
take so long for that code to run? So
代码需要花费这么长的时间来运行？所以
what's the value of Fibonacci 33? And that's what
fibonacci(33) 的值是多少？这就是
it is, it's 3 and a half million calls.
它的值 是 350 万次调用
And so even with a processor that's doing a billion instructions
因此 即使处理器每秒处理十亿条指令
a second, doing 3 and a half million recursive calls takes
做 350 万次递归调用也需要
quite a while. Each time through the call, is many more
相当长的时间 每次通过调用都
than just one instruction it's many thousands of instructions. So this
不仅仅是一条指令 它有成千上万的指令 所以这
starts to take enough time that we didn't see the result.
开始花费太多的时间使我们看不到结果
And, it wasn't only those Fibonacci 33 calls to Fibonacci 2,
并且 不仅是调用了 fibonacci(33) 次的 fibonacci(2)
we had all the other things that we had to do
为了获取 fibonacci(36) 我们还有所有
to get Fibonacci 36. But let's see that now we have
其他的事情要做 但让我们看看 现在我们有了
our faster, iteractive definition of Fibonacci that isn't doing all that duplicate
更快的 迭代的 fibonacci 定义 其不会做所有的冗余
work, that we can compute Fibonacci 36. And so that gives us this value,
工作 我们可以计算 fibonacci(36) 了 所以我们获得了这个值
so indicating that there would be about 15 million rabbits after 3 years
表明了使用 fibonacci 模型 3 年后将有
using Fibonacci's model. Let's try what we'd have after 5
约 1500 万只兔子 让我们试试我们已经过了 5 年
years, passing in 60 months, and we
传入 60 个月 然后我们
get this starting to be quite a huge
得到的数字 开始变得相当巨大
number. To try to relate to this, let's look
为了尝试认知这个数字 让我们来看看
at how long it would take for the mass
所有出生的兔子的质量
of all the rabbits that are born to exceed
将需要多长时间超过
the mass of the Earth. So the mass of the Earth is 5.9722 times 10 to the 24,
地球的质量 所以 地球的质量是 5.9722 * 10**24
and that's in kilograms, and I'm using the times
以千克为单位 我使用的 ** 符号
time notation. This gives us a power, so this
这表示的是 幂 所以这里
is 10 to the power 24. So that's one way to write 5.9 times 10 to the 24
是 10 的 24 次幂 这是 5.9 乘以 10 的 24 次幂的一种写法
kilograms, just to demonstrate the power notation, this is
为了演示一下幂符号 这里是
2 to the power 10, so we'll see the result
2 的 10 次幂 所以我们将看到结果是
is 1,024. That's what we get by multiplying 2
1,024 这是我们通过 2 乘以 2
times 2 times 2 times 2 10 times. Here we're
乘以 2 乘以 2 … 10 次 我们在这里
multiplying 10 by itself 24 times and that's a good
将 10 乘以自身 24 次 这是一个
estimate for the mass of the earth. So now to
对地球质量的很好的估计 所以现在为了
find out how many months it takes before the
解出需要多少个月 兔子质量将
mass of the rabbits exceeds the mass of the earth,
超过地球质量
we're going to have a for loop. We're going to loop from
我们将有一个 for 循环 我们要从
Fibonacci numbers, until we get to a number that exceeds
fibonacci 数字循环 直到我们获得一个数字
the mass of the Earth. We also need to decide what a mass of a rabbit is, and
其超过了地球的质量 我们还需要决定一只兔子的质量
I'm going to assume that a rabbit weighs about 2
我想假设一只兔子重约 2 公斤
kilograms. And, that's a pretty good guess for how heavy
这是一个对兔子重量不错的猜测
a rabbit is. That's assuming of course, a well
这是假设 当然是像如今
fed rabbit like we have today, not if the rabbits
这样良好喂养的兔子 而不是像
spread as fast as Fibonacci's model would suggest that
斐波纳契模型那样快速传播后的兔子
they do. So, we'll write a loop to see when
所以 我们将写一个循环来看什么时候
the mass of the rabbits exceeds the mass
兔子的质量超过地球的
of the earth. We'll start with n equals 1,
质量 我们将从 n=1 开始
and we're going to keep going until Fibonacci n
我们将继续 直到 fibonacci(n)
exceeds the mass of the earth. So, we'll go
超过地球的质量 所以 我们将计算
while Fibonacci n times the mass of the
fibonacci(n) 乘以兔子的质量
rabbit. So Fibonacci n gives us the numbers of
所以 fibonacci(n) 给我们兔子
the rabbits in month end, times the mass of
在月底的数量 乘以兔子的
the rabbit and as long as that is less
质量 然后只要它比
than the mass of the Earth, the Earth is
地球的质量要小 地球对
still safe for humanity, or at least there's some space
人类来说就仍然安全 或者至少还有一些空间
left for humans. And every time through the loop,
留给人类 每次经过循环
we'll increase n by 1. And at the end of
我们将 n 增加 1 在循环结束时
the loop, we'll print out the value of n.
我们将打印出 n 的值
We'll see where we got, and let's also print out
我们将看到我们得到了什么 让我们也打印出
the value of Fibonacci n, to see how big the
fibonacci(n) 的值 来看看这个 n
Fibonacci number of that n is. So we'll keep going
对应的斐波那契数字有多大 所以我们会继续
through the loop, as long as the Fibonacci of n times
经过循环 只要 n 的斐波那契数 乘以
the mass of the rabbit is less than the mass of the
兔子质量 小于地球的质量
Earth. And once we stop the loop that means we've exceeded
一旦我们停止循环 这意味着我们已经超过
the mass of the Earth and we'll see what the results is.
地球的质量 然后我们将看到结果是什么
So let's try running that, and, we get this result. The
所以让我们尝试运行它 然后 我们得到了这个结果
value of n is 119, so it'll only take 119 months, or
n 的值为 119 所以它只需要 119 个月 或者
just less than 10 years, until the mass of the rabbits exceeds
仅仅是不到 10 年 兔子的质量就会超过
the mass of the Earth. And this is the number of rabbits
地球的质量 这是我们那时会有的
we would have then. A pretty big number, you should
兔子数量 一个相当大的数字 你应该
be very afraid of all these rabbits. The good news
非常害怕所有这些兔子 好消息是
is that Fibonacci's model, is not actually correct. That this
这只是斐波那契模型 实际上是不正确的 这是
was a mathematical abstraction for
兔子繁殖的数学抽象
rabbit reproduction. Real rabbits actually die
真正的兔子实际上会
off after some point, and if there're too many rabbits,
在某个点之后就死亡 而且如果有太多的兔子
they don't have enough food, so they don't keep growing
它们没有足够的食物 所以它们不会一直
like the Fibonacci numbers and take over the entire planet.
像斐波那契数字一样成长 然后占领整个星球
So we should be very afraid if Fibonacci's model is correct.
所以如果斐波纳契模型是正确的话 我们应该非常害怕
It would only take 10 years for the rabbits to take over the entire planet,
只需要 10 年时间 兔子就会占领整个星球
and weigh more than the earth does itself. The good news is, it's not a very
并且比地球本身更重 好消息是 这不是一个
accurate model of how rabbits reproduce, that
关于兔子繁殖的准确模型
they don't live forever, and once there're too
它们不会永远活着 一旦有
many rabbits, they start to run out of
太多的兔子 它们就开始食物不足了
food. So they stop reproducing, and stop surviving.
所以它们会停止繁殖 停止生存